Sophie Miller

Full Stack Web Developer

OBJECTIVE

Driven, curious Full Stack Web Developer with experience working collaboratively on projects. Always seeking opportunities to learn and develop coding skills.

Pivoting from a career in project management to software engineering, bringing four years of experience & a breadth of PM knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

CODING BOOT CAMP

24 weeks / 2022 / University of Washington

Local Exchange Hub

Full stack application where users create profiles & exchange goods in their local area

Owned front & back-end development of profile page, handlebars file, public js fetch requests, & API routes using the OOP model

Implemented styling, managed project workflow, & applied agile methodology

StarParty

Front-end application delivers weather forecast & various relevant astronomy information based on user's location.

Owned Javascript, landing.js, logic for user interactivity, functions to fetch from Nasa APOD API & implemented local storage.

STARBUCKS

2022 - Present / Seattle, WA

Associate Project Manager

Manages timeline and resources for 20+creative projects on rolling basis from project planning through final execution

Gathers partner feedback and reviews project benchmarks to implement process changes and continuously improve workflow; changes implemented have reduced average project turn time by 32%

Ensures all projects are completed on time and within budget, applies agile methodology to meet unexpected needs

TAPHANDLES

2019 - 2022 / Seattle, WA

Project Manager II

Drove project roadmaps, trackers, budget analysis, while Updating budget and pricing tools to improve margins on key accounts

Marketing Coordinator

Managed e-commerce presence across DTC Shopify site and Amazon resulting in YoY e-commerce revenue growth of 28%

CONTACT

(425) 210-4447

millersg47@gmail.com

LinkedIn
Github

Portfolio

EDUCATION

WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

2014 - 2018 / Bellingham, WA B.A. Journalism

Minor International Business

WWU GLOBAL LEARNING PROGRAM

2016 / Czech Republic, Austria, Slovenia, Slovakia Studied the impacts of transition from Soviet rule to democracy on communication modes and strategies

LANGUAGES

HTML / CSS /

SQL / Javascript / JSX

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React / Bootstrap / Bulma /

OOP / jQuery / ES6 /

MySQL / Sequelize / MongoDB

Mongoose / Express / Node.js

Handlebars / Webpack / Epicor ERP

APPLICATIONS

JIRA / WordPress / Shopify /

Asana / Miro / Smartsheet /

Photoshop / InDesign / Illustrator